hello
is anybody here
where is everybody
it's pretty empty in the village there's
no one left even dark sky
he's just a zombie he's not even a
zombie villager
this is not good fortunately i have a
solution hello everybody my name is
green welcome back to another episode of
hermitcraft i've actually i think hit
the top of where i want the house to get
i've just got to finish a little bit of
work around the back but we'll get back
to that later i think we're going to
finish it off right there especially as
iskal's house is just that it's just a
little bit shorter you know mumbo's
hasn't changed stresses is there so i
think i think we're gonna win the house
competition
let's go down into
my little secret laboratory underneath
my house i've been working on it and
villager green here has been chilling
out and he's a big part of the plan it
doesn't work without him over there so
let's head down we've got to go into the
sewer system
out into this and look at this
this is my brand new secret laboratory
and if you can't tell what this is
and i'm not sure that you can by looking
at it this is a villager breeder
and i'll be honest i haven't tested it
yet this has not got two villages that's
what i'm gonna need i'm gonna need to
move villager green from up in his safe
house
into the breeder the problem is you need
two villagers to make the babies so
i'm gonna go and have to find another
one
to bring in here too we're just gonna
borrow him just for a little while but
first of all we've got to set up
everything so in order to breed it's
pretty easy you give the villagers some
food
at the right time of day
and then they have a little bit of a
recharge you give them more food and
they they basically just keep going the
only thing that you require for this to
work is beds and i've got a bunch of
beds up here but that's not enough eight
villagers to repopulate the village it's
not a lot so i thought what i would do
is i would add a bunch of
beds in here like a lot of them so this
is actually the village all i've got to
do is place a lot of beds here along
here and up here and each one of those
will be for a brand new villager at
least that's how i think it works we'll
definitely find out i think we can start
off small scale with just a few beds
maybe one line of beds for now and later
we can build this up and we can add more
beds with however many villagers we end
up creating and once we got them here
i'll show you how this works but i've
still got a bit of resource gathering to
do
in order to make this fully functional
so here's the entrance down to where the
villagers need to go so that i just got
to push them so they stand in here and
then i've actually gone and got all of
the bread that i'm going to need and i
think i'm going to add a dispenser just
to make this a little bit more automatic
than it is i don't know what i'm doing
really i don't know what i'm doing at
all i i don't even know if this is going
to work so if this works
oh boy i'm going to be so happy
so in the bread goes into this dispenser
then i'm just going to link this
redstone up to
one of the buttons that i've got on the
wall and in theory you press this
and down goes a bread
so let's get these villagers in here
including my one let's actually start
with
my villager that's probably going to be
the easiest one to do
i just got to create a little pathway
for him to walk along and hopefully it
should be a simple case of just pushing
him along
i don't want to push him like down a
hole within the base in case he takes a
load of damage and dies you have to
understand there's about two or three
villagers in this whole village left so
the death of one could mean the death of
the whole village
the stakes are pretty high on this one
the pathway is set up hopefully
the villager can't get out anywhere
along here where is he
you're free villager green you're free
that's right
shut the door in my face
come on all we got to do now is push you
along in the right direction
and safety barricade behind us
if this goes to plan he should just walk
straight into place and i wouldn't i
don't have to work at all
oh my goodness is it as simple as this
oh no
oh no i didn't see this coming
uh
i cannot lose him i literally cannot
lose this guy wait a minute can i just
push him out of the bed as well
i think i can just push him
come on in you go in you go
come on get get out of bed you're lazy
you're lazy villager you
i said out get out of bed
get out
all right we're almost there go on grian
you're a stubborn one you're a real
stubble one get out of my face
yes success
we have one
in place thank goodness now there's
truly not many survivors left but there
is one in here
impulses villager is still alive somehow
so we're going to borrow him and i mean
borrow we will we will return him
but we just need someone to help us out
here
go on in the boat in the boat yes and
we're in
now we just need to transport you safely
remember
this is the last surviving member of
hermitville don't worry we're gonna save
hermitville
oh this is so silly let's get you nice
and safe right are you ready impulse
junior
it's time for you
to make yourself useful
this one is definitely not going to play
ball i think he wants to go back to his
workstation oh
he's he lost his job go on in we go in
we go
yes okay right just one punch
and we're good
they are in
whoo that was harder than i wanted it to
be
but
i think we've got everything that we
need now so in theory just during the
day they can sense that there's beds
everywhere
we just have to give them some bread via
my automatic bread dispenser
they seem to have enough bread i can see
them
maybe i gave them too much bread is
there such a thing as too much bread
did that work
i see love hearts
no
no no no no no no that's not how this
works
you you don't get to just free roam
get back in there i'm a terrible parent
already i wonder if i need to tell
impulse that he's a father now come on
stop jumping on the bed i need you to i
need you to behave can you can you
behave for like five minutes
all right in order to get these guys
to
uh produce the baby again i need to give
them bread which is why i installed this
so hopefully if i just give them
six bread and i've already lost my child
as well where did my child go he's not
running around the system back here is
he okay well i'll tell you what that oh
[Laughter]
this child goes he just goes where he
wants
okay right you
off the bed come on moving villagers
around is a nightmare but i can't even
keep track of this child oh he's oh he's
in bed what an angel what a little angel
it seems to me that they both need to be
employed which i've now done
and they both need to eat three bread
which
i hope that i've given them i need to
know something can you dispense gree oh
you can
that is amazing
hello son
you know he looks he looks a lot like
his dad he does
[Laughter]
i'm not sure how this works at all i'm
gonna be honest i don't know how this
works
it seems to be working
but i'm not sure what i'm doing right
and wrong
so i've had very limited success with
these guys but they did manage to
produce about three villagers i have no
idea what i've done wrong here
but um
it's gotten a bit messy you see so this
didn't go well but the villagers that
went through
the back of this
round the side well they've been busy
and now i've got a little bit of an army
going on
it's not all of them but you can see
these guys are breeding and you can see
the experimentation i've had to do i
have no idea how they see beds
but
it's working this is working this is the
way to do it put them in a big glass jar
surround it with loads of beds i've even
like produced like a little uh gap here
so that they can see the beds i just
can't figure it out i honestly can't are
they even let's see like there's loads
of hearts but are they producing babies
looks like there's one in there
it depends if they can see the beds or
not and that's where it gets complicated
i've had to move all the beds from the
sleeping area because i thought this was
where they would see it
apparently not now remember
that it takes 20 real life minutes for
all of these babies to turn into adults
so
i've been
at this for about two hours now trying
to figure out how these villages work i
need to do more research but i think
i've got it down i think i've got enough
villagers here to repopulate
hermitville or as it might now be called
greenville i just have to dispense all
these heads on the passing villagers
and then i'll leave some of them blank
i'll leave some of them uh available for
for the taking so that everyone can have
a villager but for the most part they're
gonna be
they're gonna be how did you get out
no bad
bad and then when all of these guys are
adults and they've got their mask on
we're gonna set them loose into the
village itself
whoa whoa
excuse me no
how did you
now that's a bad sign
and they're breeding again this is oh
wow look at all those
this shouldn't take any time at all all
right i'll be back then when all of
these guys are ready to be released
because i've got to admit this took way
longer than i intended it was much
harder than i intended
but ultimately successful and look how
messy this is this laboratory has turned
into a village
in no time at all i have no idea how to
make farms and i probably shouldn't do
it
the experiment
is complete
that's right i have been
a scientist this whole time my
experiment may have failed over there
but all of these guys are ready there's
some without any jobs at all sorry
without any green heads at all so that
other hermits can take them and
claim them for their own and i think we
can call this pretty much repopulated
amazing so what's next we need to go and
release these guys which means we need
to make a way out for them i've been
underground for about three hours so
it's good to be out i think the exit was
just about here so all we're going to do
is add a water bucket there
and then we're going to
create a bubble elevator that they're
all going to walk up and be free in the
village
soul sand at the bottom
and bubble elevator up we can release
all of these because hopefully these
villagers will all just take a bet if we
like went and put beds in all of these
places again the village should spring
back to life in theory everyone should
go and find a workstation
and
well the village should be fixed and it
only took several hours of my time
all right guys
it's time for me to let you go
the doors are open
i want you guys to be free so this is
what it's like on the inside of this
it's not particularly pleasant
oh no no there's too many of you i don't
like it
there we go
goodbye
off you go
might take a while to get these guys to
leave but
i'm pretty sure
that this should work
freedom
oh bubble elevators are the best thing
ever added to this game
we need to get you impulse junior back
to impulse
because
your job here is done
congratulations i need to get both of
you back out of here
well i'm going to call this a total
success however they are all hanging
around here
because they are still trying to get to
their beds and their workstation when i
destroy those
they should all become unemployed and
spread throughout the village or at
least that's the that's the dream some
of them are heading over in this
direction they seem to be
doing their thing ah at least the
village feels alive now which is
which is amazing
and what's this over here
rendog's breeding pit shop coming soon
um
no way
why didn't i think of selling them i've
just released them all into the wild for
free
oh i'm so sorry red i've totally i've
just i've just ruined ren's business
here i don't think anyone's gonna be
buying your villagers now ren because
there's plenty of them around in fact
there's possibly too many but i made too
many because
as you can see there's probably going to
be a few casualties along the way
this is absolutely amazing so i think we
need to go and delete all that stuff
down there and call this a complete
success i don't really know what to do
with my lab anymore this has kind of
served its purpose a little bit we can
bring impulse back to where is impulse
where's impulse junior gone green's
there we need to get you back upstairs
for sure
how did you get in there
well i suppose that makes things a
little easier
it's taking a little while but impulse
junior has just got back into his house
oh boy i had to make a whole tunnel
system you know funnel system to get him
back home but that's brilliant but i
feel like i have a a care of duty to
tell impulse
hey impulse you're a father now to the
whole village
gee i wonder what he's going to make of
that because he of course has no idea to
him his villager has just stayed in that
house and nothing has happened but all
of a sudden there's
green and villager everywhere i'm so
glad that this is done because that has
been hours of my life which i'm never
going to get back but i had to do it in
order to save the village from complete
devastation and i think it's been a
total success
hopefully we won't have too many
casualties they're all wandering around
most of them are fishermen because of
all the barrels but i have been placing
a few lecterns around so that maybe
they'll uh take those jobs on as well
but i think that is more than enough of
grianville for now i think it's
definitely greenville like there's too
many greens around this is absolutely
fantastic i can't wait to see how people
react to this
right let's head back to the shopping
district because i've been working on
something else in the background
oh no
oh no no no
i thought they looked like there was
much less
oh this isn't gr this is not good
this is not good at all
this is exactly why
we produce too many
because
stuff like this happens
they walk through i completely blanked
on the fact that there was a portal in
the middle of nowhere that might even
explain where all of the villagers have
gone in the first place
you know what you could stay there i've
got enough through now all right let's
crack on with what we were supposed to
be doing
i'm glad that i actually saw that
because that could have been well that
could have put us back exactly where we
were
and i'd have to do that all over again
i'm pretty sure the villagers won't ever
give me a good price now what i've been
working on and have finally finished
is the elytra course i've been working
steadily on this for the last few
episodes
green's fun elytra course and i'm still
working out some of the kinks there's
definitely something to be said for
the amount of uh sharp turns there are
and stuff it is is pretty difficult
so what i need to do is i've made a
bunch of banners some with like arrows
this is the best i could do i'm not very
good with the whole banner thing but
look that's totally an arrow it's
totally an arrow down it's the best i
can do
but this should help if there's places
where people get a bit stuck but i'm
hoping that everyone will just learn the
course and of course i am
making some diamonds here so
it costs one diamond to do a run you
lose if you uh die
but you get penalty points if you just
take damage and
my goodness is this is really difficult
course like to to get a no hit run on
this
is very challenging i'm so i'm also
selling rockets as well tango hasn't
stocked up his shop in a long time
but uh i'm selling four stacks for one
diamond is a really good price and
hopefully i can keep on top of this as
well so there's there's a good amount of
diamonds in this chest as well so
hopefully people get obsessed with
trying to beat my score and it costs
them loads of diamonds but of course i
need to offer a final prize as well but
with that i think i need to show you
guys the full thing and i need to try
and do this
with no hits whatsoever i need to try
and set a score i don't know how to do a
timer properly so i guess i won't know
the score until i edit this
um but i think it's time to do our first
test run a little bit nervous
but let's give it a go this is going to
be the one to set the time and if you do
take damage it's only a one second
penalty point but that will add up if
you take a lot of damage right here we
go
through the first one and then you gotta
go up right i obviously know this bit
off by heart and so do you guys because
you've seen me do it about 100 times
already so i don't even need to take you
through this
so far so good no hits
keep up the rocket maybe i should limit
the amount of rockets you can use maybe
one stack so that you can't just hold
down spam like i do
that's kind of a difficult one to get
through i am doing so well here at the
moment no hit run so far now this is the
difficult part because cub in his
infinite wisdom to try and make this
even harder added a load of bamboo
and
it's very difficult oh that's one second
one second added
it's going very well
oh it's going very
well i've added one second so far
that's a very difficult one to get
through and then this is all new course
here
and this should take us all the way back
so i do need to add the banners so that
people know where all of the rings are i
really need to concentrate
i've got one hit on this
and then i think i'm home free there's a
little bit of lag going on
oh oh yeah right turn hard right hard
right that that is gonna need some
arrows
oh no two seconds
oh it's totally possible to do this
without any hits if i did that with two
hits i could definitely do that with no
hits
and then on to the final run
there we go
i have no idea how long that took i
won't know until i edit it but that will
be the final score and once i know it
i'm going to put it up on here and that
will be the time to beat if only i could
make an in-game redstone clock like you
press the button then you go and then
when you get through the final ring you
press the button so i have a penalty
point or i have two penalty points so i
have to add two seconds onto my score oh
man that is a pretty intense elytra
course i did some testing with uh rendog
and he actually died several times so
i'm not gonna be too surprised if that
happens there is a bed here to set your
spawn and uh maybe i could even do it at
a did you die box
i think that i think that's great
actually yeah i'm gonna do that as well
so there's definitely a bit of
fine-tuning to do i need to make sure
people know where they're going but i'm
gonna tell all the other hermits to make
sure to watch my video on
how uh where the course goes i forgot at
the end that it's a really hard right
turn
but that oh that is so fun i actually
was a little bit nervous doing that so
to get just two hits on that especially
through the bamboo bit that is that is
the toughest part
scar has just found the village with all
of the people
oh man that's brilliant scar has found
the village and he's uh he's a little
bit shook if we can get just one sale
from the did you die box uh my
hermitcraft experience will be funded a
little longer i'm running out of
diamonds as i always do because i keep
putting all of my money into these
business ventures i've spent lots of
diamonds creating this thing but this is
by far one of the coolest things i've
made so far it may not look that pretty
i am going to improve it especially like
the cave and some of the rings look a
bit naff but i just wanted to get it
done first so that people can start
playing it because i know that a lot of
people are very excited to try it out
but hopefully i can make a bit of
diamonds as well so you know if people
try 10 times
i could make like 60 diamonds from that
and then they can use my rockets and
they can pay there and then if they die
they can buy a did you die box and this
is excellent on its own
this is going very very well
and that brings me on to the final
project to talk about this episode
obviously a lot of things are getting
done the projects are being done the
laboratory got finished and i
repopulated the village saving it
heroically with the help of impulse the
elytra course is now finished and sahara
is also well on its way so just a little
bit of an update i have messaged the
redstone guys isko and mumbo and i've
sort of said you know get a move on guys
what's going on
and hopefully they're going to take a
look at it but from what i've been told
things are looking incredibly good and
hopefully within the next few episodes
we can get sahara officially open we've
got sahara out in hermitville that is
open now we've got sahara here which is
well on its way and hopefully i can
start making my diamonds back i'm pretty
sure i have not made a profit this whole
season and that's about to change
because all of my shops and businesses
and gizmos are about to go live
so i'm afraid that's it from me everyone
thank you very much for watching i hope
you've enjoyed this episode as always
and if you did if you're a new
subscriber because there's been a lot of
you recently make sure you hit subscribe
if you're not because that's uh you know
it helps me out and stuff uh look at my
outfit this is uh
mad scientist grian i don't use this one
very often so it's cool to get this one
out i feel like cub fan and
yeah
i feel a lot like cub fan
yeah i'm gonna i'm gonna get changed i
need to get back into my my usual
clothes bye everyone bye